<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started: Evacuation</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Evacuation">
      "Run for your lives!"
      <p>
	The most common reason for a node to leave a cluster is
	shutdown for scheduled maintenance. With the increasing
	frequency of software updates, this is becoming more and more
	common and with the growing number of nodes in your cluster,
	more and more complex and error prone.
      </p>
      <p>
	Every time a node leaves a cluster, the sessions that it is
	carrying will become unavailable, unless they can be evacuated
	to surviving nodes.
      </p>
      Let's take a look at WADI doing this.
      <p>
	We start a <font color="red">red</font> and <font color="green">green</font> node.
      </p>
      <p>
	When everything has settled down, create a session on <font color="red">red</font> with e.g. :<a href="http://localhost:8080/wadi/session.jsp">http://localhost:8080/wadi/session.jsp</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
	Shutdown <font color="red">red</font> gently (i.e. ctl-c).
      </p>
      <p>
	<font color="red">red</font> will say something like this :
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 21:24:55:568 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: 9B8858BA311C365632247E66387415BA : memory -> cluster (65 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	<font color="green">green</font> should say e.g. :
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  Utils - -motion: 9B8858BA311C365632247E66387415BA : cluster -> memory (20 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	and the Partition Master (in this case <font color="green">green</font>, because it is the only surviving node):
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  LocalPartition#67@green - -evacuate {9B8858BA311C365632247E66387415BA : red -> green}
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	Note that Partitions are evacuated first and then Sessions
	are evacuated to their respective Partitions. This ensures
	that the sessions are left in the most efficient place that
	they can be and are scattered evenly around the surviving
	nodes.
      </p>
      <p>
	In this way, WADI maintains the availability of sessions beyond the lifetime of their container.
      </p>
    </section>
      <p>
      Try creating more than one session on a node in a larger cluster
      and then shutting it down - you may need to restart your
      browser, use more than one browser, or a tool like Jakarta
      JMeter. You should see sessions evacuating from this node to
      different nodes all across the cluster.
      </p>
  </body>
</document>
