<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started: Location</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Location">
      "Location, Location, Location!"
      <p>
	The Location of resources is all-important in a Cluster. The
	sum of all e.g. Sessions, may be too large for copies of all
	of them to be held on every node (not to mention the issues
	associated with trying to keep all these copies up to date).
      </p>
      <p>
	A WADI Partition is responsible for maintaining a Map of
	session-id:session-location for a distinct subset of the
	cluster's sessions.
      </p>
      <p>
	Each node can deduce the Partition to which a session belongs by
	applying a simple algorithm to its ID.
      </p>
      <p>
	Each node knows which node is responsible for each of the fixed
	number of Partitions. (This information is disseminated around
	the cluster every time ownership of a Partition changes).
      </p>
      <p>
	Thus, it follows that any node can find the whereabouts of any
	session, by using its ID to decide who knows where it is and
	then asking them.
      </p>
      <p>
	The flipside of this is that each time a session is created,
	migrated, or destroyed, its corresponding Partition must be
	notified of this change. (In future, WADI will try to ensure
	that sessions are generally created and destroyed on the node
	that holds their Partition, so minimising network traffic -
	but in exceptional cases a session may have to be moved
	elsewhere)..
      </p>
      We can watch this occurring in WADI.
      <p>
	Start your <font color="red">red</font> and <font color="green">green</font> nodes.
      </p>
      <p>
	Create a Session on the <font color="red">red</font> node,
	using e.g. the following link: <a href="http://localhost:8080/wadi/session.jsp">http://localhost:8080/wadi/session.jsp</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
	Note that <font color="red">red</font> will say something like:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 17:54:29:292 GMT [DEBUG] ClusteredManager - -creation: A931056AACF210B8058025F67E1204CB
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	and whichever node is the Partition Master for the newly
	created session will report its notification e.g. thus (in
	this case Partition #3, currently serviced by <font
	color="green">green</font>, is reporting that it has just been
	notified of the [re]location of a session on <font
	color="red">red</font>):
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 17:54:29:271 GMT [DEBUG] LocalPartition#3@green - -insert: A931056AACF210B8058025F67E1204CB {red}
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	Your browser should be returning a page looking something like this:
      </p>
      <p>
	<img src="../images/location.0.jpg"/>
      </p>
      <p>
	The background of the page is <font color="red">red</font>
	because it was served from the <font color="red">red</font>
	node. There is a table containing one cell, because we have
	only touched the page once. This cell is <font
	color="red">red</font>, because it was allocated on the <font
	color="red">red</font> node.
      </p>
      <p>
	Refresh the page a couple of times. Notice that, since
	everything is now local, we do not see any more
	location-oriented messages. You should end up with something
	like this :
      </p>
      <p>
	<img src="../images/location.1.jpg"/>
      </p>
      <p>
	Since we have touched the page three times now on the <font
	color="red">red</font> node, we have three <font
	color="red">red</font> cells.
      </p>
      <p>
	Now we can try asking for the same session on the <font
	color="green">green</font> node. Try hitting e.g. <a
	href="http://localhost:8081/wadi/session.jsp">http://localhost:8081/wadi/session.jsp</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
	<font color="red">red</font> should say something like this:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 17:59:52:207 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: A9518C9C6BAB34CDBEE765DF60AE6A76 : memory -> emigration:green (74 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	<font color="green">green</font> should say something like this:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 17:59:52:195 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: A9518C9C6BAB34CDBEE765DF60AE6A76 : immigration:red -> memory (40 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	and the Partition Master should report the change of session location:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  LocalPartition#46@red - -move: A9518C9C6BAB34CDBEE765DF60AE6A76 {red->green}
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	Finally your browser should now have a page like this:
      </p>
      <p>
	<img src="../images/location.2.jpg"/>
      </p>
      <p>
	The table may be thought of as a history of the session's
	location in the cluster. You should be able to see from the
	colour of the page and the new cell, that the session has now
	moved to the <font color="green">green</font> node.
      </p>
      <p>
	Just to be sure, refresh the page a couple of times.
      </p>
      <p>
	<img src="../images/location.3.jpg"/>
      </p>
      <p>
	You get the idea...
      </p>
      <p>
	NOTE - we should demonstrate the destruction of the session
	and its removal from the Partition as well...
      </p>
      <p>
	The transparent relocation of sessions beneath incoming
	requests is an important part of WADI's ability to ensure that
	request and session meet somewhere in the cluster in order to
	correctly render the response.
      </p>
    </section>
      <p>
      Try starting a number of different WADI nodes, then creating and moving a session around them...
      </p>
  </body>
</document>
