<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started: Partitioning</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Partitioning">
      "Divide And Conquer"
      <p>
	Partitioning is a strategy commonly used to aid in
	scalability. You divide a large problem into smaller pieces
	that are demonstrably independant of each other. Because they
	are independant of each other, these problems may be solved
	concurrently with no contention on any shared resource.
      </p>
      <p>
	Many existing clustering solutions require that a cluster is
	manually partitioned at configuration time and that this
	structure remains static throughout the lifetime of the
	system.
      </p>
      <p>
	Fortunately for this demo, WADI partitions its problem space
	dynamically. A fixed number of Partitions is specified at
	configuration time. Ownership of these is then renegotiated
	dynamically between a cluster's nodes as they join and leave
	the cluster.
      </p>
      We can watch this happening in a very simple WADI demo.
      <p>
	We start a <font color="red">red</font> node. As it comes online WADI outputs e.g. the following:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:30:54:444 GMT [DEBUG] SimplePartitionManager#red - -allocating 72 partitions
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	Then we start a <font color="green">green</font> node. As it comes up the <font color="red">red</font> node says:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:36:36:720 GMT [DEBUG] DIndex#red - -node joined: green
	</code>
	<br/>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:36:36:988 GMT [DEBUG] SimplePartitionManager#red - -released 36 partition[s] to green
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
      and the <font color="green">green</font> node says:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:36:36:979 GMT [DEBUG] SimplePartitionManager#green - -acquired 36 partition[s] from red
	</code>
	<br/>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:36:36:996 GMT [DEBUG] DIndex#green - -node joined: red
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	so you can see that <font color="red">red</font> has shared its partitions with the new member, <font color="green">green</font>.
      </p>
      <p>
	If you shutdown <font color="green">green</font> (gently via e.g. ctl-c), you will see it say:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:40:01:750 GMT [DEBUG] SimplePartitionManager#green - -released 36 partition[s] to red
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	and <font color="red">red</font> says:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:40:01:696 GMT [DEBUG] DIndex#red - -node left: green
	</code>
	<br/>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 16:40:01:707 GMT [DEBUG] SimplePartitionManager#red - -acquired 36 partition[s] from green
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	This ability to share responsibility for servicing a fixed set
	of Partitions is at the very centre of WADI's architecture.
      </p>
    </section>
      <p>
      Try starting a number of different WADI nodes and watching the sharing of Partitions across the cluster...
      </p>
  </body>
</document>
