<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started with WADI</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Getting Started with WADI">
      <p>
	To familiarise yourself with WADI, we provide a number of
	simple demonstrations that you may walk through.
      </p>
      <p>
	If you are pressed for time, forget about the installation
	step and running the s/w. Just go straight to the demos. You
	should be able to glean quite a lot from just reading through
	them.
      </p>
      <p>
	WADI-2.0M1 is a technology preview release. We are not yet
	production ready. In order to get best results from the
	software, certain temporary guidelines are suggested.
	<ul>
	  <li>
	    leave a reasonable pause (e.g. 5 seconds) between starting
	    and stopping nodes.
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    do not 'kill -9' a node.
	  </li>
	</ul>
	These guidelines are to help to you avoid stumbling on issues
	in the current release of which we are aware. They will be
	relaxed as soon as these issues are resolved.
      </p>
      <p>
	The demonstration web application relies on the tying of the
	web session to the browser via a cookie. Please ensure that
	you have cookies enabled in your browser.
      </p>
      <p>
	NOTE: Some browsers (Konqueror), include the server port in a
	cookie's domain. This makes them unsuitable for this
	demonstration, since you will be making requests through more
	than one port on the same host, whilst requiring that the same
	cookie is used for all requests. This issue does not affect
	the load-balancing demonstration, since all requests are made
	through a single port - the one on which the load-balancer is
	listening.
      </p>
      <p>
	<ol>
	  <li><a href="./install.html">installation guide</a> (REHASH)</li>
	  <li>
	    walk through some demos:
	    <ul>
	      <li><a href="./partitioning.html">partitioning</a> demo</li>
	      <li><a href="./location.html">location</a> demo</li>
	      <li><a href="./evacuation.html">evacuation</a> demo</li>
	      <li><a href="./paging.html">paging</a> demo</li>
	      <li><a href="./loadbalancing.html">load balancing</a> demo (mod_jk2) (REHASH)</li>
	      <li><a href="./jmxmonitoring.html">JMX monitoring</a> demo (mc4j) (REHASH)</li>
	    </ul>
	  </li>
	</ol>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
