<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started: Paging</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Paging">
      "..."
      <p>
	As the number and size of the sessions on a node increases,
	the ability of the JVM to manage its heap decreases, leading
	to reduced performance. The physical footprint of the JVM on
	the box also increases, necessitating the purchase of more
	memory and larger, faster, more expensive boxes.
      </p>
      <p>
	By paging out inactive sessions to a cheaper, slower storage
	medium, space in the more expensive, faster medium (memory)
	can be preserved. If the session is required after this event,
	it will be paged back in. If it is not, it may simply expire
	on disc. (Note that some types of Listener require
	notification on Session death and may cause the session to be
	reloaded as it is destroyed).
      </p>
      <p>
	If a session that is paged out is required by another node, it
	may be located, read in from local disc by one node, then,
	without being deserialised (one of the most expensive things
	that distributed apps commonly do), be moved to the node on
	which its request has arrived. Here it can be deserialised and
	used to service the request, remaining on this node, until
	being required elsewhere, paged out again, invalidated by its
	application or timed out by the container.
      </p>
      <p>
	The WADI demo webapp comes with a MemoryEvicter, which is set
	to sweep memory every 10 seconds and evict sessions which have
	not been used for more than 10 seconds. We would not recommend
	these settings for production, but they are useful for
	demonstration purposes.
      </p>
      Let's try it.
      <p>
	We start a <font color="red">red</font> and <font color="green">green</font> node.
      </p>
      <p>
	When everything has settled down, create a session on <font
	color="red">red</font> with e.g. :<a
	href="http://localhost:8080/wadi/session.jsp">http://localhost:8080/wadi/session.jsp</a>
	and wait for between 10 and 20 seconds, until you see <font
	color="red">red</font> say something like :
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 21:56:06:325 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: 7F9BF12C222FCC99607CAFF98D0EAEF3 : memory -> exclusive disc (12 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	<font color="red">red</font> is telling you that it has moved
	a session out of memory and onto exclusively owned disc -
	i.e. disc that only <font color="red">red</font> has access
	to.
      </p>
      <p>
	Reload your page - adding another cell to the table. <font color="red">red</font> says:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 22:04:17:455 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: 7F9BF12C222FCC99607CAFF98D0EAEF3 : exclusive disc -> memory (3 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	and the session moves up the stack and back into memory.
      </p>
      <p>
	Let it page out again, then ask for it on <font color="green">green</font> - e.g. : <a href="http://localhost:8081/wadi/session.jsp">http://localhost:8081/wadi/session.jsp</a>
      </p>
      <p>
	<font color="red">red</font> says:
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 22:56:05:260 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: C8C00E6E6A7F47C6264F12F39EB7A312 : exclusive disc -> emigration:green (66 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	You can see that the session was never deserialised by <font color="red">red</font> - it travelled straight from disc...
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 22:56:05:251 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: C8C00E6E6A7F47C6264F12F39EB7A312 : immigration:red -> memory (39 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	...into memory on <font color="green">green</font>, where it was deserialised.
      </p>
      <p>
	Let it sit on <font color="green">green</font> until it pages out again...then gently (ctl-c) shutdown <font color="green">green</font>:
      </p>
      <p>
	The session is evacuated directly from disc on <font color="green">green</font>...
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 23:00:45:442 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: C8C00E6E6A7F47C6264F12F39EB7A312 : exclusive disc -> cluster (24 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	... to disc on <font color="red">red</font>.
      </p>
      <p>
	<code>
	  2005/12/07 23:00:45:434 GMT [DEBUG] Utils - -motion: C8C00E6E6A7F47C6264F12F39EB7A312 : cluster -> exclusive disc (5 millis)
	</code>
      </p>
      <p>
	Note: No deserialisation occurred at all.
      </p>
    </section>
      <p>
      By allowing the paging out of inactive sessions WADI can greatly
      decrease hardware requirements within a cluster and improve
      performance of existing deployments.
      </p>
  </body>
</document>
