<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started with WADI</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Getting Started: Installation">
      <p>
	To install WADI:
	<ul>
	  <li>
	    Either:
	    <ol>
	      <li>download a copy of WADI 2.0M1</li>
	      <li>unpack it somewhere</li>
	      <li>set WADI_HOME to this dir and export it</li>
	    </ol>
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    Or:
	    <ol>
	      <li>check out the latest WADI src from CVS</li>
	      <li>Build it</li>
	      <li>set WADI_HOME to the top of this tree and export it</li>
	    </ol>
	  </li>
	</ul>
      </p>

      <p>
	WADI nodes use a machine generated unique id to distinguish
	each other. For the purposes of logging and monitoring, WADI
	expects each node to also be given a more user-friendly id
	(ideally unique). This second id - the node's name - is used
	to label its configuration. The WADI demonstration uses
	colours (<font color="red">red</font>, <font
	color="green">green</font>, <font color="blue">blue</font>,
	...) as node names. Configurations corresponding to these
	names may be found in $WADI_HOME/conf.
      </p>
      <p>
	WADI integrates with a number of different web containers. To
	walk through the 'Getting Started' documentation, you will
	need at least one of the following installed and available to
	WADI. Choosing more than one container will allow you to test
	WADI's ability to cluster a mixed set of containers.

	<ul>
	  <li>Installing <a href="./tomcat.html">Tomcat 5.0.x, 5.5.x</a></li>
	  <li>Installing <a href="./jetty.html">Jetty 5, 6</a></li>
	  <li>Installing <a href="./geronimo.html">Geronimo-1.0</a></li>
	  <li>Installing <a href="./jboss.html">JBoss-4.x</a></li>
	</ul>
      </p>

      <p>
	WADI nodes speak to each other via asynchronous messages over
	ActiveMQ. ActiveMQ may be configured with a variety of
	protocol stacks. Ultimately, WADI will use ActiveMQ's peer://
	protocol. This allows peers in a cluster to message each other
	directly. Currently, due to a couple of issues in the peer://
	stack, the demonstration needs to be run on the tcp://
	stack. This necessitates the running of a standalone message
	broker to which all nodes connect and via which all messages
	are exchanged. This is an obvious single point of failure and
	will be removed as soon as the issues with peer:// have been
	resolved. We are working on this as a priority.

	<ul>
	  <li>Download a copy of <a href="http://dist.codehaus.org/activemq/distributions">activemq-3.2.1</a></li>
	  <li>Unpack it somewhere</li>
	  <li>Set ACTIVEMQ_HOME to this dir and export it</li>
	  <li>To start up the ActiveMQ broker: cd $ACTIVEMQ_HOME/bin; sh activemq.sh</li>
	  <li>To shut down the ActiveMQ broker: Ctl-c it</li>
	</ul>
      </p>

    </section>
  </body>
</document>
